Register of the Claire Sterling papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Claire Sterling papers
1936-1994
96053
Hoover Institution Archives
82 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (34 linear feet)
The collection contains writings, notes, correspondence, reports, photocopies of trial transcripts and interrogations, clippings, other printed matter, sound recordings, and photographs related to the Mafia, organized crime in Italy and the United States, international organized crime, and international terrorism.
Sterling, Claire.
Access
Collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collections
Antonio Albano legal motion, Hoover Institution Archives
Dorothea Price Farquharson papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Genesis, rise and decline of terrorism in Italy conference papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Paul B. Henze papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1919 Born, Queens, New York
Circa 1940 Graduated from Brooklyn College
1945 Master's degree, Columbia Graduate School of Journalism
Circa 1945 Worked for Overseas News Service
1946 Author, Our Goal Was Palestine
1949-1968 Wrote for The Reporter until it ceased publication in 1968
1951 Married Thomas Sterling
Circa 1951 Moved to Italy Became the Rome correspondent for an American news agency
1969 Author, The Masaryk Case
1981 Author, The Terror Network
1984 Author, The Time of the Assassins
1990 Author, Octopus: The Long Reach of the International Sicilian Mafia
1994 Author, Thieves' World: The Threat of the New Global Network of Organized Crime
1995 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career of Claire Sterling, an American journalist who lived in Italy for much of her life. The collection contains writings, notes, correspondence, reports, photocopies of trial transcripts and interrogations, clippings, other printed matter, sound recordings, and photographs related to the Mafia, organized crime in Italy and the United States, international organized crime, and international terrorism.
After graduating from Columbia University, Sterling began her career in journalism, working for the Overseas News Service and writing for The Reporter. The Biographical file contains clippings on Sterling's life, as well as appointment books.
Thomas Sterling, the husband of Claire Sterling, was an author who wrote novels and travel books. The Thomas Sterling file includes drafts for several of his monographs, including The Amazon and A Pride of Ambassadors. This file contains many of Thomas Sterling's diaries and notebooks, several of which depict his travels in Africa and were perhaps used as material for some of his travel books.
The majority of Correspondence was sent and received by members of the Sterling family, including letters sent to Claire and Thomas by their children, Abigail and Luke. Also included are detailed letters sent to Pan Sterling, grandmother of Abigail and Luke, from a friend traveling abroad.
As a journalist, Sterling covered stories on political situations in Europe and the Middle East, writing about events that took place during the Cold War. Over her long career, Sterling wrote for publications such as The Atlantic Monthly, Financial Times, The New York Times, The Reporter, and The Washington Post. In 1969, Sterling published her first full-length book, The Masaryk Case, in which she argued that the Czechoslovak foreign minister Jan Masaryk had been assassinated. Her next book, The Terror Network, explored international terrorism, while Octopus focused on the Sicilian Mafia. In The Time of the Assassins, Sterling presented the "Bulgarian Connection" theory as the motivation behind the 1981 assassination attempt on Pope John Paul II. Her last published book, Thieves' World, described the connections between various mafia groups and other organized crime syndicates. The Writings series includes articles that Sterling wrote for various publications, and drafts, reviews, and correspondence related to her monographs.
Sterling kept Notes detailing her research and interviews for her writings. The collection contains a series of notebooks that Sterling labeled by location, as well as loose pages of notes and a series of index cards related to her research for The Terror Network.
The Subject file, which contains the bulk of the material in the collection, includes Sterling's notes and gathered clippings on crime, drug traffic, and mafia organizations in various counties, which she used as research and references for her books and articles.
In addition, the collection includes Sound recordings related to Sterling's work and Photographs of the Sterling family.
Source: Pace, Eric. "Claire Sterling, 76, Dies; Writer on Crime and Terror." New York Times 18 June 1995. Accessed on April 2013 through: http://www.nytimes.com/1995/06/18/obituaries/claire-sterling-76-dies-writer-on-crime-and-terror.html
Journalists.; Mafia.; Organized crime--Italy.; Organized crime--United States.; Organized crime.; Terrorism.
- Biographical file, 1976-1994 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains address books, appointment books, and biographical clippings.
  - Address book and list of contacts, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Appointment book, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Appointment and address book, 1981 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Appointment book, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Itineraries, undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - List of contacts, 1988, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Travel documents, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Correspondence, 1936-1990 (Box 1-3)
  The correspondence is divided into two subseries: general and family correspondence. The general correspondence contains letters that Sterling received or wrote, while the family correspondence contains letters sent to and from various Sterling family members, including letters received by Pan Sterling.
  - General, 1985-1990 (Box 1-2)
    - General, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Publisher and financial correspondence binder, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Sterling, Thomas, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Family correspondence, 1936-1974 (Box 2-3)
    - Sterling, Abigail, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
      Letters to Claire and Thomas Sterling, with two letters to Annie
    - Sterling, Luke, 1974, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
      Letters to Claire and Thomas Sterling
    - Sterling, Pan (Box 2-3)
      - General, 1936, 1970, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
      - Letters to Pan from Marguerite, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 2: 6-8)
        Detailed letters describing Marguerite's travels
      - Letters to Pan from Marguerite (Contd.), 1967-1970 (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
- Thomas Sterling file, 1947-1976 (Box 3-7)
  Includes diaries and notebooks of Thomas Sterling, some of which concern his travels in Africa. Although only a few diaries are signed with his name, it is likely that the rest were created by Thomas Sterling based on handwriting and content. Includes writings of Thomas Sterling.
  - Diaries and notebooks (Box 3-5)
    - Undated (Box-folder 3: 4-10)
    - Undated (Box-folder 4: 1-7)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 4: 8)
      Documents a trip through Africa
    - 1951 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - [1974] (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Israel, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Writings (Box 5-7)
    - The Amazon (Box 5-6)
      - Expense report, 1973 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - Proofs, undated (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - Proofs and research, 1973, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Chapter 1 of unidentified book, annotated typescript, undated (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - "Macchia: The Encroaching Deserts", undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - A Pride of Ambassadors, annotated typescripts and notes, undated (Box-folder 6: 6-10)
    - A Pride of Ambassadors, annotated typescripts and notes (Contd.), undated (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - "Time's Bloodless Island", 1976 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Writings, 1965-1994 (Box 7-16)
  Contains correspondence, drafts, and printed copies of Sterling's articles and books. Includes writings on topics such as crime, international terrorism, and the Mafia.
  - General, typescripts and printed copies, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Agca, Mehmet (Box 7)
    - "Agca's Other Story: The Plot to Kill Walesa," printed copy, 1984 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Articles, 1984 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Research and responses to Sterling's articles, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
  - Aswan dam writings and notes, undated (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Atlantic Monthly, typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
  - Book proposal, "Sins of Omission: A Suggested Book on Terrorism", 1990 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    General note
    Originally filed with "New terrorist wave" subject file
  - "The Bulgarian Connection," Wall Street Journal, printed copy, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Financial Times, typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 8: 5-6)
  - Il Giornale, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Indira Gandhi articles, typescripts, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    See also Subject file
  - "Italian Terrorists: Life and Death in a Violent Generation," printed copy, 1981 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Herald Tribune and Washington Post, typescripts and printed copies, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - La Stampa, typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 9: 1-3)
  - Liggio, Lunciano, typescript and printed copy, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - NATO article, undated (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - New York Times and other publications, typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box-folder 9: 6-7)
  - Octopus (Box 9-10)
    - Dust jacket, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Reviews (Box 9-10)
      - Britain, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 9)
      - France, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 10)
      - Italy, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - United States, 1990 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Penthouse, 1990 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - "Qaddafi Spells Chaos," printed copy, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Reader's Digest, 1979 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Schedule of meetings for France article for USRD, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - The Terror Network (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and itineraries, 1979 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Reviews, 1981, 1983 (Box-folder 10: 7-10)
  - Thieves' World (Box 10-15)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 10: 11-15)
    - Correspondence and typescripts, 1994 (Box-folder 10: 16)
    - Cover art, undated (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - Proofs, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Research (Box 11-14)
      - General, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 11: 2-4)
      - Prologue, 1993, undated (Box-folder 11: 5)
      - Chapter 1, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 11: 6)
      - Chapter 3, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 11: 7)
      - Chapter 4, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
      - Chapter 6, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 12: 4)
      - Chapter 7, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 12: 5)
      - Chapter 8, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 12: 6)
      - Chapter 9, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - Chapters 11 and 12, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 13: 2-4)
      - Chapter 13, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
      - Chapter 13 (Contd.) (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - United Kingdom edition, Crime Without Frontiers, correspondence and printed copy, 1994 (Box-folder 14: 2-4)
    - Typescripts (Box 14-15)
      - Undated (Box-folder 14: 5-6)
      - Chapter 1, annotated, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
      - "Final Draft," annotated, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 1-3)
  - Time of the Assassins tour schedules, 1984 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Washington Post, typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence (Box 15-16)
    - 1968-1978 (Box-folder 15: 6-9)
    - 1968-1978 (Contd.) (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 16: 2-3)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 5)
- Notes, 1962-1992 (Box 17-22)
  Includes loose pages of notes, notebooks, and index cards created by Claire Sterling in relation to her writings.
  - Note pages, 1977-1986, undated (Box 16-17)
    - Undated (Box-folder 16: 6-8)
    - 1977, undated (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - 1985, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Carmine, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Notebooks, 1962-1992 (Box 17-22)
    - General (Box 17-20)
      - Undated (Box-folder 17: 3-8)
      - Undated (Box-folder 18: 1-9)
      - Undated (Box-folder 19: 1-9)
      - Circa 1985 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
      - Circa 1988 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - Circa 1992 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Asia, undated (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Cortona, Italy, undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Cyprus, 1964 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - France, undated (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Germany, undated (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Israel, undated (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Italy crisis, 1963 November (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - La Jacono and Prague, undated (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Poland, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - Poland and Czechoslovakia, undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Rhodesia, 1963 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Russia, undated (Box-folder 21: 6-7)
    - South, 1962 June (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Spain, undated (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Spain, 1965 January (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Switzerland, 1991 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Warsaw, 1990 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Washington, undated (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Venezuela, circa 1987 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Index cards, undated (Box 22-23)
    Used as research for The Terror Network
    - Curiel (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Algeria (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Argentina (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Austria (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - China (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Cuba (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Cyprus (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - France (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Great Britain (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - International government (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - The International (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Iran (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Italy
      - Fioroni (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Terror and Mala (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Petra and Krause (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Feltrinelli (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Brigate Rosse (Red Brigades) and Red Army Faction (RAF) (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Vianale and Nuclei Armati Proletari (NAP) (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Ties to others (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - Partito Comunista Italiano (PCI) and terrorism (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Japan (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Latin America (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Libya (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Palestinians
      - Fatah (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Other (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP) (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Carlos (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Russia (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Spain (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Sweden (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Switzerland (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Trotskyites (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Turkey (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - U.S.A. (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - West Germany
      - Red Army Faction (RAF) (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - Gabriele Kröcher-Tiedemann (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - Bommi Baumann (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Women (Box-folder 23: 2)
- Subject file, 1960-1994 (Box 23-81)
  Includes notes, clippings, printed matter, and correspondence related to crime, terrorism, and various mafias. Used as research for Claire Sterling's writings.
  - Agca, Mehmet and Pope John Paul II, 1984 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    See also Writings
  - Amendolito, Salvatore, pizza case testimony, 1986 (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
  - Amendolito, Salvatore, pizza case testimony (Contd.), 1986 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Anti-drug plans, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Anti-laundering, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Anti-Mafia Commission, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 24: 4-6)
  - Anti-Mafia, washing, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Anti-Mafia, washing (Contd.), 1983-1991 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Arms traffic, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Art theft, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Asylum, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 25: 4-6)
  - Autonomy motivation (Abbate-Santiapichi), undated (Box-folder 26: 1-3)
  - Belgium, 1991 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Bellinzona, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 26: 5-6)
  - Bulgaria, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 26: 7-8)
  - Buscetta, Tommaso, 1984-1986, undated (Box-folder 27: 1-6)
  - Buscetta interrogation, circa 1984 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Buscetta interrogation (Contd.), circa 1984 (Box-folder 28: 1-2)
  - Camorra, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Chinese triads, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Cocaine, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 28: 5-6)
  - Commersant: The Russian Business Weekly, 1992 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Commersant: The Russian Business Weekly (Contd.), 1992 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Communism, 1976 (Box-folder 29: 2-5)
  - Corte D'Assise of Rome pleadings, volume 1-3, circa 1986 (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
  - Corte D'Assise of Rome pleadings, volume 4, circa 1986 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Court of Rome pleadings, judgement given by Ernesto Cudillo, 1978 (Box-folder 31: 2-5)
  - Court of Rome pleadings, judgement given by Ernesto Cudillo, 1978 (Box-folder 32: 1-3)
  - Crime (Box 32-33)
    - 1974-1978 (Box-folder 32: 4)
    - 1975-1980 (Box-folder 32: 5)
    - 1976-1980, undated (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - 1991-1992 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 33: 7-8)
  - Crime and scams Europe-wide, 1989, 1992 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Crime books, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 34: 2-6)
  - Crime books (Contd.), 1969-1978 (Box-folder 35: 1-2)
  - Crime reports (Box 35-36)
    - Undated (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 35: 5)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
  - Cuba, 1962-1979 (Box-folder 36: 3-4)
  - Curiel, Henri case, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Curiel, Henri case (Contd.), 1977-1982 (Box-folder 37: 1-5)
  - Cyprus, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 37: 7)
    Includes correspondence about The Masaryk Case
  - The Day Is Born of Darkness by Michael Dyomin, printed copy with notes, 1976 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Digennaro report, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 38: 2-4)
  - Drug traffic, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Drug traffic, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Drugs, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 39: 2-3)
  - Dutch and Germany, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - East Europe, central crime, 1991 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - East Europe investment, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Economics, 1992, undated (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - European Community (EC) (Box 39)
    See also Schengen Agreement
    - Beyond European Community, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Economic union, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 39: 9)
    - European Community security, Schengen Agreement, immigration, and asylum, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 39: 10)
    - Financial union, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 39: 11)
    - Political union, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 39: 12)
  - Egypt and Communism in Europe, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 39: 13-14)
  - Egypt and dams, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 40: 1-3)
  - France (Box 40)
    - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 40: 4-5)
    - 1989-1992 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Gambino, John (Box 40-41)
    - General, 1973-1990 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - General (Contd.), 1973-1990 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Court papers, 1988 (Box-folder 41: 2-4)
    - Gambino bust, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Germany, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
    Includes correspondence of Sterling
  - Great Ruble Scam, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 42: 3-6)
    Includes documents regarding Philip Wainwright, Michael Preisfreund, and Leo Wanta, and correspondence concerning Thieves' World
  - Great Ruble Scam (Contd.), 1990-1994 (Box-folder 43: 1-2)
  - Hungary and Turkish Mafia, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - India and Indira Gandhi, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 43: 4-6)
  - India and Indira Gandhi (Contd.), 1970-1975 (Box-folder 44: 1-3)
  - Inter-government, Europe, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - International terrorism, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 45: 1-6)
  - Interpol, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 46: 1-2)
  - Iran, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - Irish Republican Army (IRA), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 46: 4-5)
  - Israel, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - Italian autonomy, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 46: 7)
  - Italian Court of Appeal; Rocco Chinnici and Greco; Sindona and bankruptcy, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 47: 1-5)
  - Italy, file 1 (Box 48)
    - Brigate Rosse (BR) and Partito Comunista Italiano (PCI), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Brigate Rosse (BR) and Red Army Faction (RAF), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 2)
    - Italian terrorists, Attacks, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 3)
    - Italian terrorists, ties with Mala, 1979 (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Law and order, secret services, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - Italy, file 2 (Box 48)
    - General, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Italian terrorists, methods and personalities, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 7-8)
    - Patrica and Serbregondi, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - Vianale and Nuclei Armati Proletari (NAP), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Italy, file 3 (Box 49)
    - Feltrinelli, Giangiacomo, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Fioroni, Carlo and Carlo Saronio, 1978, undated (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Moro, Aldo, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - Italy, file 4 (Box 49-50)
    - Contorno, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 49: 4)
    - Mafia and drugs, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - Mafia and the law, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 49: 6-7)
    - Mafia and the law (Contd.), 1985-1988 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Mafia capos and practices, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - 'Ndrangheta, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 50: 3-4)
    - Sicilian economy, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 50: 5)
    - United States and Italy collaboration, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Italy, file 5, 1984-1993 (Box-folder 50: 7-8)
  - Italy, file 5 (Contd.), 1984-1993 (Box-folder 51: 1-4)
  - Italy, file 6, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Japan, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - Kröcher-Tiedemann, Gabriele, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 51: 7)
  - Latin America, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Laundering cases, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Laundering, United States, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Libel, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 52: 4)
    Includes documents on the Pizza Connection and Napoli family
  - Libya, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Maastricht Treaty, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 52: 6-7)
    Includes indexes of other resources
  - Maastricht Treaty (Contd.), 1985-1992 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Mafia, file 1 (Box 53-54)
    - Anti-Mafia, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Camorra, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 53: 3)
    - Clan Dei Catanesi, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 53: 4)
    - French connection, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - History, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 53: 6)
    - Mafia and church, 1982 (Box-folder 53: 7)
    - Mafia wars, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 53: 8)
    - Mafia war on cops, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Palermo crackdown, 1984 (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Mafia, file 2 (Box 54-55)
    - Arms and drugs, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 54: 3)